govhs.org 2017-11-20

# Privacy Policy | The Virtual High School

## Privacy Policy

Privacy Statement, effective 11/22/16:

VHS established this privacy policy to let you know how we collect, use, share, and protect information that we may gather from our websites, information that we may collect from you outside of our website, such as by phone, FAX, or through postal mail, as well as information about you passed through to third party tools used in VHS's learning environment. This policy does not apply to information about you collected by online educational resources and content hosted on non-VHS servers which is linked to or otherwise accessible from within VHS. The information collected or received by external online educational resources and offerings that are not directly integrated into VHS's learning environment are subject to their own privacy policies.

### Security of your information

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. We also use Secure Sockets Layer protocol to protect sensitive personal information throughout all of our web systems/websites.

Student educational records are protected by VHS, Inc. as required by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and similar state laws. VHS strictly adheres to Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act policies and regulations.

### Personal information provided by parents about children

We understand that our student users who are under 13 years of age need special safeguards and privacy protection, and it is our intent to fully comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. The VHS corporate website does not collect personal information from children online at any point. You can review certain personal information that VHS has regarding your child by making such a request in writing to [privacy@TheVHS.org](mailto:privacy@TheVHS.org). Please be aware that some personal information relating to your children's educational records may not be able to be disclosed by VHS due to state and/or federal law.

You can request that your children's personal information not be used by VHS, and any affiliates and/or vendors acting on behalf of VHS, by making a request in writing to VHS. Please be aware that in order to participate with VHS, some information must be collected and shared. If you opt out, your student may not be able to continue to take courses through VHS.

### How we use student personally identifiable information

VHS may use student personally identifiable information for educational support purposes for children enrolled in VHS courses. Such support includes but is not limited to: academic progress, test scores, attendance, and general student guidance.

VHS may pass student personally identifiable information to integrated third party tools used to enrich student activity and experience. When VHS passes such personally identifiable information to integrated third party tools, it does so with the minimum amount of information required by that tool. Our integrated vendors understand they have no rights to any student data we provide and have agreed to maintain confidentiality of any such data that gets passed to them.

We may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis. Such third parties are prohibited from using student personally identifiable information except to provide these services to VHS, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

### Personally identifiable information we collect

If you contact us or sign up for VHS newsletters, webinars, courses, or other offerings we will collect the information you submit to us, whether through an online form, email, phone, FAX, or other communication. If you register your student directly or indirectly with us through a local school affiliate you are providing us personally identifiable information about you and/or your children. The types of personally identifiable information you or an affiliated school may be asked to provide about your student include, but are not limited to: first name, middle name, last name, street address, gender, date of birth, phone number, email address, and graduation year. The types of personally identifiable information a parent or guardian may be asked to provide include but are not limited to: title, first name, last name, address, phone number, and email address.

### How we use non-student personally identifiable information

If you contact us directly, we will respond to your request or take other suitable action. The information regarding your contact remains within VHS and VHS will not share, sell, or trade any personally identifiable information to any third party.

We may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from VHS and our affiliates. We may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services. We may also, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party without your explicit consent.

You may choose not to receive marketing or promotional emails from VHS by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of the emails we send you. Additionally, you may unsubscribe by contacting us directly by phone or mail. Note that VHS participants cannot opt out of non-marketing communications.

Our work, including our web statistics, is not automatically available to the government or to the public, and any information we choose to share will be on an aggregated, non-identifying basis.

We will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on VHS Inc. or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of VHS; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of VHS services, or the public.

### Non-personally identifiable information we collect

We may also use "cookies" to track when you have returned to a specific page. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. We may use cookies to help us understand the products and pages that interest you, personalize your experience on our website, and recall your specific information such as personal information, billing addresses, and so on to simplify the process of recording your information on subsequent visits.

Beyond that, the only information about your visit that we receive is the standard Internet log information collected by all websites. This includes the host system from which your visit originated and the time and duration of your visits to our pages. No personally identifiable information is collected about you in this process, and the log information is combined with all other visits to create traffic statistics. Such statistics help organizations know overall traffic levels to their website.

### Definitions of terms used in this privacy policy

"VHS, Inc.", "The Virtual High School", or "VHS" are all refer to The Virtual High School, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization that provides learning opportunities through online courseware either directly or indirectly to students of all ages.

Personally identifiable information, as defined by the [U](http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-122/sp800-122.pdf)[nited States Government Accountability Office](http://www.gao.gov/new.items/d08536.pdf): is "any information about an individual maintained by an agency, including (1) any information that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual's identity, such as name, social security number, date and place of birth, mother's maiden name, or biometric records; and (2) any other information that is linked or linkable to an individual, such as medical, educational, financial, and employment information."

Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act "...is a Federal law that protects the privacy of student education records." The U.S. Department of Education provides [additional details about Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act](http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html) from their website.

The Federal Trade Commission's Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and refers to individuals under the age of 13. The Federal Trade Commission provides [additional details about Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy) from their website.

"Third Party Tools" refer to software and resources integrated with VHS's learning environment that add depth and breadth to VHS course offerings. Some tools include anti-plagiarism software, blogs & wikis, eBooks, etc.

### Changes to the privacy policy

We will occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect feedback from faculty, staff, customers, and to incorporate any changes to privacy laws.  We will inform faculty and staff of changes to this privacy policy via our weekly announcements and we encourage you to check back often to review our policy to stay informed of changes.  If you wish to be informed via email, we encourage you to sign up for our news and announcements here.  The effective date of this Privacy Policy is documented at the beginning of the Privacy Policy.

[Click here](http://go.thevhs.org/l/86702/2016-04-25/27pd9w) to receive annual updates on our Privacy Policy.
